<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SRPG on Mike Brave</title>
    <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/tags/srpg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SRPG on Mike Brave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://michaelbrave.github.io/tags/srpg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ogre Battle - Game Mechanics Study</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/blog/ogre-battle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/blog/ogre-battle/</guid>
      <description>I want to explore the mechanics of Ogre Battle because I want to clone a lot of it&amp;rsquo;s features into a game I&amp;rsquo;m working on. Not a direct clone but heavily inspired by it to the point of almost using it as a template.
Ogre Battle Released on the SNES in 1993 and later for the PSX in 1997, this game named after not one but two Queen songs is one of my favorite games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ogre Battle 64, Person of Lordly Caliber- Game Mechanics Study</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/ogre-battle-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/ogre-battle-64/</guid>
      <description>This is the sequel to Ogre Battle and the mechanis are derivative and very similar, so I&amp;rsquo;ll only take notes on what&amp;rsquo;s different.
6 Different Endinges - Very Different
Story Heavy - Lots of World Building Bosses are throwaway bosses
Difference From SNES Game Chapters Sub Missions Take over stronghold, mission requirements mission overview and advice 3x3 grid moves you use, amount of moves, defense, which units can be attack, which units attack you 5 characters to a team, big units count as 2 back and side attacks less moves when in back row more equipment leaderless running away is different already liberated towns, neutral towns and conqured towns some towns resist guard, follow make camp - regain stamina gain new soldiers for winning/strongholds - these are basic units Hugo Report Relationship Tree entering strongholds talk to villagers heavy / light units / Ranged Units magic combo attacks xp from every battle not just kills permadeth of units / witch revives / but squad death is dead item carrying</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tactics Ogre, Let Us Cling Together - Game Mechanics Study</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/tactics-ogre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/tactics-ogre/</guid>
      <description>Playstation Version or PSP Remaster?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
