<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike Brave</title>
    <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mike Brave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelbrave.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory Of Happiness</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/hapiness-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/hapiness-theory/</guid>
      <description>A Definition
What Makes People Happy?
Mastery - Being good at what you do, competence
Belonging - Social relationships
Autonomy - Freedom to make decisions
Needs satisfied
Happiness is independent of outcomes but we allow our feelings about outcomes to direct it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes That Help You Grow In A Happier Direction</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/happier-direction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/happier-direction/</guid>
      <description>Inviting the World To Play With You
How to play, everything is play
The Homeless Guy In Austin About overcoming fear of Dancing “I Play with you, You Play With Me”
Creating sandboxes to play in, the Wisdom of Teagan
Humility is a Willingness To Learn, an Openness
On Gratitude, The Seed of Happiness
We never achieve things ourselves, we are just a piece of that achievement, your parents raised you, your friends supported you, your society shaped you, you are the core piece, but only a piece, respect and give credit, let them share your accomplishments and achievements because it is theirs too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awe, Wonder &amp; Pleasant Surprises</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/awe-wonder-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/awe-wonder-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Embracing and Encouraging Surprise and wonder in our lives
What is Delight?
Find Joy in the unexpected
“Oh that’s interesting”
“I never would have thought of that”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Practical Is The Act Of Seeing Through Illusions</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/practical-is-seeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/practical-is-seeing/</guid>
      <description>Instead of buying into the culture/media you can see it as it is
But if you go too far off the path of normal you will be considered insane
Beware of Tinfoil Hat Conspiracy Theories, usually the bigger the theory the less true it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Picture Thinking</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/big-picture-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/big-picture-thinking/</guid>
      <description>What Actually Matters?
The shortness of life - the many ways life could end, the many ways the world could
How Warren’s car crash made him quit sweating the small stuff, and made his life better
The ability to die, fragility and a shelf life is what allows ethics?
Love is worth fighting for.
Easing the suffering of others is worth fighting for.
The small and tender moments are worth giving everything else up for, don’t be a workaholic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Moralities and The Shifting of Self</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/changing-moralities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/changing-moralities/</guid>
      <description>Morality Is A Kind Of Cowardice, A Conscience Makes Cowards Of Us All
But that isn’t something to look down on, just something to be aware of
“I Don’t Want That Anymore” - Ambitions Change With Life
The tempering of ambitions and how we shift as people
Parents changing direction of what they want to new goals that include or feature their children, it’s not wrong, but it is kinda unexpected</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difficult Truths And How To Accept Them</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/difficult-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/difficult-truths/</guid>
      <description>If it Pisses You Off, There’s a Bit Of Truth in it, Usually&amp;hellip;
It hits hard because you know you should have taken care of it already
A hard truth that needs to be faced
This isn’t always true as sometimes it’s just ridiculous that they even suggest it and it’s angering because of how defamatory it is, but if it was truly ridiculous you would probably laugh instead of getting angry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Strategies And Techniques For A Happier Life</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/happier-life-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/happier-life-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Forgiving Yourself, Forgiving The World I am weak willed at times, be forgiving to yourself Everyone else is just as human as you are, be kind to them. The buddhist idea that life is suffering, so be kind We all kind of suck so be kind to yourself Humanity Is Having Compassion And Suffering With Someone Life Will Provide, You Need Very Little To Live During the camino, people came and went, things sorted themselves out, what you needed was enough, life provided, wisdom was all around, beauty in unlikely places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How People Are</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/how-people-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/how-people-are/</guid>
      <description>Our Flaws Make Us Better - Why It’s Ok for Smart People to Do Dumb Things
I&amp;rsquo;m always shocked when people I admire do dumb things, but never when I do. I don&amp;rsquo;t even look down on them, it&amp;rsquo;s just an “oh, that&amp;rsquo;s odd”. We are all just human. It&amp;rsquo;s better this way
Art Shapes Our Values - Our Surroundings Influence Us
Example - Having Flowers at a school, changes how the school is, how the students treat it and how much learning can take place there</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>knowledge notes</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Relationships and Related Defining Love  What Is Love?  Jon and watching his daughter grow Why I feel loss from distance The need for individuality, love requires friction else it’s an object/slave relationship  Seeing people as people and not just what they can do for you   Often we choose what is familiar instead of what is good for you - some people like to be treated poorly and would be suspicious if you treated them well People who feel like home love shouldn’t have constraints, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit in a box, it’s not negative or fearful, it’s opposite is shame Love is perfect kindness Opening of the heart is the beginning of love There can be many paths and kinds of love, it’s not a hierarchy of strength but different things for different people at different times 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live An Interesting Life</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/living-interesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/living-interesting/</guid>
      <description>Say Yes as Often as You Can
Always Choose The Better Story
What You Want To Do Is Cheaper Than You Think, Find a Way</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Is All Around Us, We Just Don’t See It</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/magic-all-around-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/magic-all-around-us/</guid>
      <description>We Often Don’t See Because We Don’t Know How To See Yet
The Hippies Were Right - Undiscovered Things That Matter &amp;amp; Influence
There Is Value In Stating The Obvious
Common Sense is a Lie
The Problem Isn’t The Problem We Think It Is - i.e. Piracy Is About Service, Not Cost
How a Thing Is Communicated Isn’t The Thing Itself
The subject and how it’s communicated, often grouped together, not actually the same thing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing Exists In A Vacuum</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/nothing-exists-in-a-vacuum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/nothing-exists-in-a-vacuum/</guid>
      <description>Everything is Connected, Ecosystems Within Ecosystems
Your body and your mind aren’t separate, similarly your cells and bacteria are part of you too
Dependencies and Chain Reactions
Network Effects
Sometimes a thing by itself won’t do anything, but combined with the right something else will create extraordinary results.
Thinking With Systems
A business is a collection of systems, usually ran by people</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pain Isn’t Antagonistic to Happiness, But it’s Easier to Be Happy When Pain is Managed</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/pain-vs-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/pain-vs-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Non-Attachment and Letting Go - Our Expectations are the Painful Part
Goodbyes as an Act of Love - Ash and freeing his pokemon, because he really cared about them
You can’t trust anything to be there tomorrow, people leave or die, currency loses value, governments fail, websites disappear
Every freedom we have could one day disappear, it has happened before, vigilance and care, and a long memory are required to keep it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragedy, Loss and Hope</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/tragedy-loss-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/tragedy-loss-hope/</guid>
      <description>Tragedy and Loss Should Be Treated As the Catalysts of Choice, Show Your Cards or Don’t
It reframes the conflict, now it’s real
The reframing loss/death
These are moments given to us to now choose a path, there is pain, but there is also options of play, we always have some choice to make.
Tragedy is When Poor Choices Are Made, and Consequences Cascade From it
Loss Due to Poor Behavior Feels Like Justice - But it Isn’t</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truly Living</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/truly-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/truly-living/</guid>
      <description>The Point Of The Game Is To Keep Playing, To Play a Beautiful Game
Leap Before You Look - Stop Living a Sterile Life
Avoiding Pain Is Keeping Me From Living
A ship is safe on the docks but that’s not what ships are for.
Inventiveness, Playfulness and Living
There is no reason it can’t be fun
Life Is Resource Management (see boxing)
Really Living vs Being Responsible
A good story doesn’t start with “so I followed the rules and was truly safe”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If It&#39;s Worth Doing Well, It&#39;s Worth Doing Poorly</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/post/do-it-poorly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/post/do-it-poorly/</guid>
      <description>I once heard a saying that if &amp;ldquo;something is worth doing well, then it&amp;rsquo;s worth doing poorly&amp;rdquo; in this particular case it was in reference to keeping a diet and was along the lines of &amp;ldquo;done is better than perfect&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;better something than nothing&amp;rdquo;. So keeping with the diet example, every time I&amp;rsquo;ve failed at keeping a diet it&amp;rsquo;s been something along the lines of quitting because &amp;ldquo;I already messed up yesterday&amp;rdquo;, while the times I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to keep a diet were the times I was allowed to make mistakes, or when I had already factored in something like a cheat day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shoe Dog: A Memoir by the Creator of Nike</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/review/shoe-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/review/shoe-dog/</guid>
      <description>This is a memoir by/for Phil Knight, one of the founders of Nike and covers his life from the time of finishing college until Nike went public. It’s rare that I can read a book that I can’t put down and ends up cutting into my sleep because I just want to read one more chapter or know “what’s going to happen next” or wonder “how are they going to pull that off”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build in the open</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/post/build-in-the-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/post/build-in-the-open/</guid>
      <description>Why have my notes be public? This is in large part due to two different ideas.
The first is that building in the open aka building with the garage door open allows for better feedback loops with other people. People can tell me where/how I&amp;rsquo;m wrong, maybe my wisdom/failing can help someone else, those who are curious about me can know what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking and instead of having something private I can instead be building a kind of resource that could create a kind of creation momentum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroes Being Human</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/post/heroes-being-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/post/heroes-being-human/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was fortunate to find PBS - The Making of Ponyo and it was insightful into the of someone I&amp;rsquo;ve alway looked up to profesionally, Hayao Miyazaki.
I think the best parts weren&amp;rsquo;t the parts they focused on, they were mostly trying to capture his process (which if I&amp;rsquo;m being honest is very similar to video game concept art processes), but what was even better was watching him procrastinate, and search for inspiration and dealing with his own internal doubts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ogre Battle - Game Mechanics Study</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/post/ogre-battle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/post/ogre-battle/</guid>
      <description>I want to explore the mechanics of Ogre Battle because I want to clone a lot of it&amp;rsquo;s features into a game I&amp;rsquo;m working on. Not a direct clone but heavily inspired by almost like using this game as a template or a foundation.
Ogre Battle Released on the SNES in 1993 and later for the PSX in 1997, this game named after not one but two Queen songs is one of my favorite games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m what happens when you take an artist, turn them into a designer and then later a developer.
My lifelong mission (other than finding the perfect lemonaide) is to use technology to make better and cheaper art. This explains my interests in Neural Networks (especially being used to create things), it&amp;rsquo;s why I love things like procedural generation, and It&amp;rsquo;s why I get excited about game engines being used in ways other than for making games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books to Read</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/books-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/books-to-read/</guid>
      <description>Empire of Imagination - the story of Gary Gygax and D&amp;amp;D Michael Witwer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Games and Assets With Fans</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/community-collab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/community-collab/</guid>
      <description>Sony Player Studio
Unreal Tournament (new)
Dota 2 Item Sales
Skyrim - Pay for Mods
Sonic Mania
Real/Original Early Access (Minecraft)
Streaming Designing / Youtube Designing
Level Editors (Warcraft 3, Little Big Planet)
Skyrim Mods</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamelist</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/gamelist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/gamelist/</guid>
      <description>GrimGrimoire - PS2 - 2D RTS/SRPG https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GrimGrimoire
13 Sentinels: Aegis Rim - PS4 - Sidescroller/RTS?
Risk - Board Game - Tactical
Dynasty Tactics - PS2 - Tactical/Wargame
Valkyria Chronicles - PS3/PS4 - SRPG/Turn Based Shooter See shining blade and shining ark for psp, they seem similar
Wizardry 8
Darkest Dungeon
Dragon Age: Origins see shining resonance for ps3
Chrono Cross
Star Ocean: The Second Story
Odin Sphere Leifthrasir
Golden Sun - GBA - RPG</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Branding of Game Companies</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/game-branding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/game-branding/</guid>
      <description>brand is how peopele describe your company not what you say.
Final Fantasy Realm Reborn
Warcraft 3 Reforged
Star Wars Battlefront 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Am I Doing Now?</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/now/</guid>
      <description>June 2020
Learning:
I&amp;rsquo;m learning how to make a game using Unreal Engine 4. I&amp;rsquo;m making something that&amp;rsquo;s a spiritual successor to Ogre Battle: March of the Black Queen for SNES, but with RTS elements and a customizable AI Gambit System (like Final Fantasy 12 or Dragon Age).
I&amp;rsquo;ve also started working through Harvard CS50 again as I never finished it and would like to.
Reading:
I&amp;rsquo;m reading &amp;ldquo;Procedural Storytelling in Game Design&amp;rdquo; by Tanya X.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>