<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts on Mike Brave</title>
    <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drafts on Mike Brave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best in What Way, For Who, When?</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/best/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/best/</guid>
      <description>Every Choice is a Tradeoff Everything is a tradeoff, always. The longer I live the more evident this is true. I used to be and still sometimes struggle with being a perfectionist, I like to weigh all the options, see every possibility before committing to a decision, sometimes even going back over it again and rethinking the decision, this has never served me well.
“A good plan, violently executed now, is better than a perfect plan next week” — George Patton</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Picture Thinking</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/big-picture-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/big-picture-thinking/</guid>
      <description>One of the most productive things I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to do has been to cut things out of my life because they weren&amp;rsquo;t the most important. Focus is as much what you don&amp;rsquo;t do as what you do. So it becomes even more important to recognize and prioritize the things that actually matter, especially if these are along the important and impactful but not urgent spectrum.
So then I have to ask myself, what are the things that actually matter?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro Posts</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/micro-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/micro-posts/</guid>
      <description>an idea stolen from https://jetholt.com/may-2020-microblogs/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awe, Wonder &amp; Pleasant Surprises</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/awe-wonder-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/awe-wonder-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Cultivating curiosity and wonder are what allow me to be productive, to get things done and to keep procrastination at bay, I find that they are also core emotions to my functioning well as a person and key my own happiness or contentment.
I believe that the distillation of it is feedback and enjoying that feedback. Look at a baby splashing water, they are surprised by how their actions caused a reaction, they are surprised and often delighted by that direct feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory Of Happiness</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/hapiness-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/hapiness-theory/</guid>
      <description>A Definition
What Makes People Happy?
Mastery - Being good at what you do, competence
Belonging - Social relationships
Autonomy - Freedom to make decisions
Needs satisfied
Happiness is independent of outcomes but we allow our feelings about outcomes to direct it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes That Help You Grow In A Happier Direction</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/happier-direction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/happier-direction/</guid>
      <description>Inviting the World To Play With You
How to play, everything is play
The Homeless Guy In Austin About overcoming fear of Dancing “I Play with you, You Play With Me”
Creating sandboxes to play in, the Wisdom of Teagan
Humility is a Willingness To Learn, an Openness
On Gratitude, The Seed of Happiness
We never achieve things ourselves, we are just a piece of that achievement, your parents raised you, your friends supported you, your society shaped you, you are the core piece, but only a piece, respect and give credit, let them share your accomplishments and achievements because it is theirs too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Practical Is The Act Of Seeing Through Illusions</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/practical-is-seeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/practical-is-seeing/</guid>
      <description>Instead of buying into the culture/media you can see it as it is
But if you go too far off the path of normal you will be considered insane
Beware of Tinfoil Hat Conspiracy Theories, usually the bigger the theory the less true it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Moralities and The Shifting of Self</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/changing-moralities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/changing-moralities/</guid>
      <description>Morality Is A Kind Of Cowardice, A Conscience Makes Cowards Of Us All
But that isn’t something to look down on, just something to be aware of
“I Don’t Want That Anymore” - Ambitions Change With Life
The tempering of ambitions and how we shift as people
Parents changing direction of what they want to new goals that include or feature their children, it’s not wrong, but it is kinda unexpected</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difficult Truths And How To Accept Them</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/difficult-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/difficult-truths/</guid>
      <description>If it Pisses You Off, There’s a Bit Of Truth in it, Usually&amp;hellip;
It hits hard because you know you should have taken care of it already
A hard truth that needs to be faced
This isn’t always true as sometimes it’s just ridiculous that they even suggest it and it’s angering because of how defamatory it is, but if it was truly ridiculous you would probably laugh instead of getting angry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Strategies And Techniques For A Happier Life</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/happier-life-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/happier-life-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Forgiving Yourself, Forgiving The World I am weak willed at times, be forgiving to yourself Everyone else is just as human as you are, be kind to them. The buddhist idea that life is suffering, so be kind We all kind of suck so be kind to yourself Humanity Is Having Compassion And Suffering With Someone Life Will Provide, You Need Very Little To Live During the camino, people came and went, things sorted themselves out, what you needed was enough, life provided, wisdom was all around, beauty in unlikely places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How People Are</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/how-people-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/how-people-are/</guid>
      <description>Our Flaws Make Us Better - Why It’s Ok for Smart People to Do Dumb Things
I&amp;rsquo;m always shocked when people I admire do dumb things, but never when I do. I don&amp;rsquo;t even look down on them, it&amp;rsquo;s just an “oh, that&amp;rsquo;s odd”. We are all just human. It&amp;rsquo;s better this way
Art Shapes Our Values - Our Surroundings Influence Us
Example - Having Flowers at a school, changes how the school is, how the students treat it and how much learning can take place there</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas That Changed My Life</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/ideas-that-changed-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/ideas-that-changed-my-life/</guid>
      <description>Toy Technologies Hidden In Plain Sight Mayan Wheels on toys vs Game Engines used in non gaming fields
Reslient Systems &amp;gt; Efficient Systems Potato Famine Vs Incas Democracy is a resilient system Dinosaurs were efficient/specialized self reliance is another word for poverty
A Good Photograph is When I Would Rather Look at The Photo Than The Initial Subject Similar to the medium is the message but rather it&amp;rsquo;s more about choosing which medium would best represent what you wanted to get out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>knowledge notes</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Relationships and Related Defining Love  What Is Love?  Jon and watching his daughter grow Why I feel loss from distance The need for individuality, love requires friction else it’s an object/slave relationship  Seeing people as people and not just what they can do for you   Often we choose what is familiar instead of what is good for you - some people like to be treated poorly and would be suspicious if you treated them well People who feel like home love shouldn’t have constraints, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit in a box, it’s not negative or fearful, it’s opposite is shame Love is perfect kindness Opening of the heart is the beginning of love There can be many paths and kinds of love, it’s not a hierarchy of strength but different things for different people at different times 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live An Interesting Life</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/living-interesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/living-interesting/</guid>
      <description>Say Yes as Often as You Can
Always Choose The Better Story
What You Want To Do Is Cheaper Than You Think, Find a Way</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Is All Around Us, We Just Don’t See It</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/magic-all-around-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/magic-all-around-us/</guid>
      <description>We Often Don’t See Because We Don’t Know How To See Yet
The Hippies Were Right - Undiscovered Things That Matter &amp;amp; Influence
There Is Value In Stating The Obvious
Common Sense is a Lie
The Problem Isn’t The Problem We Think It Is - i.e. Piracy Is About Service, Not Cost
How a Thing Is Communicated Isn’t The Thing Itself
The subject and how it’s communicated, often grouped together, not actually the same thing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing Exists In A Vacuum</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/nothing-exists-in-a-vacuum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/nothing-exists-in-a-vacuum/</guid>
      <description>Everything is Connected, Ecosystems Within Ecosystems
Your body and your mind aren’t separate, similarly your cells and bacteria are part of you too
Dependencies and Chain Reactions
Network Effects
Sometimes a thing by itself won’t do anything, but combined with the right something else will create extraordinary results.
Thinking With Systems
A business is a collection of systems, usually ran by people</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pain Isn’t Antagonistic to Happiness, But it’s Easier to Be Happy When Pain is Managed</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/pain-vs-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/pain-vs-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Non-Attachment and Letting Go - Our Expectations are the Painful Part
Goodbyes as an Act of Love - Ash and freeing his pokemon, because he really cared about them
You can’t trust anything to be there tomorrow, people leave or die, currency loses value, governments fail, websites disappear
Every freedom we have could one day disappear, it has happened before, vigilance and care, and a long memory are required to keep it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragedy, Loss and Hope</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/tragedy-loss-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/tragedy-loss-hope/</guid>
      <description>Tragedy and Loss Should Be Treated As the Catalysts of Choice, Show Your Cards or Don’t
It reframes the conflict, now it’s real
The reframing loss/death
These are moments given to us to now choose a path, there is pain, but there is also options of play, we always have some choice to make.
Tragedy is When Poor Choices Are Made, and Consequences Cascade From it
Loss Due to Poor Behavior Feels Like Justice - But it Isn’t</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truly Living</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/truly-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/truly-living/</guid>
      <description>The Point Of The Game Is To Keep Playing, To Play a Beautiful Game
Leap Before You Look - Stop Living a Sterile Life
Avoiding Pain Is Keeping Me From Living
A ship is safe on the docks but that’s not what ships are for.
Inventiveness, Playfulness and Living
There is no reason it can’t be fun
Life Is Resource Management (see boxing)
Really Living vs Being Responsible
A good story doesn’t start with “so I followed the rules and was truly safe”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Chess - Game Mechanics Study</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/auto-chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/auto-chess/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Majong? Also Card Games
Tempo, synergies
Personal Thoughts: could you combine them like in Yugi-oh for playstation?
See Also Dota Underlords Teamfight Tactics Hearthstone autoplayer? Forgot the name</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>King of Dragon Pass - Game Mechanics Study</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/king-of-dragon-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/king-of-dragon-pass/</guid>
      <description>Released in 1999, this is one of those games that some people say nothing like it has come out since.
Turn based strategy and role playing game. it&amp;rsquo;s like a primitive city builder, kinda.
backstory choices to create a culture for your team
appointing leaders and advisors the hints they give based on how skilled they are
Personal Thoughts: I expected more combat and less city planning choices.
The focus on the gods and the mythology is interesting, I should incorporate something like that into my game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ogre Battle 64, Person of Lordly Caliber- Game Mechanics Study</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/ogre-battle-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/ogre-battle-64/</guid>
      <description>This is the sequel to Ogre Battle and the mechanis are derivative and very similar, so I&amp;rsquo;ll only take notes on what&amp;rsquo;s different.
6 Different Endinges - Very Different
Story Heavy - Lots of World Building Bosses are throwaway bosses
Difference From SNES Game Chapters Sub Missions Take over stronghold, mission requirements mission overview and advice 3x3 grid moves you use, amount of moves, defense, which units can be attack, which units attack you 5 characters to a team, big units count as 2 back and side attacks less moves when in back row more equipment leaderless running away is different already liberated towns, neutral towns and conqured towns some towns resist guard, follow make camp - regain stamina gain new soldiers for winning/strongholds - these are basic units Hugo Report Relationship Tree entering strongholds talk to villagers heavy / light units / Ranged Units magic combo attacks xp from every battle not just kills permadeth of units / witch revives / but squad death is dead item carrying</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tactics Ogre, Let Us Cling Together - Game Mechanics Study</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/tactics-ogre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/tactics-ogre/</guid>
      <description>Playstation Version or PSP Remaster?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/cultivating-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/cultivating-agency/</guid>
      <description>inspired by this thread https://twitter.com/shreyas/status/1276956836856393728?s=20 and https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8LPwyy4scAc
don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start, figure out where to start
everything is a mess, start cleaning and organizing
no consensus, clarify
no vision or strategy, start making one
it may not be your job but you can help facilitate
don&amp;rsquo;t understand, start learning
too much to do, prioritize the right things
traumatic life creates someone who believes that reality is a second best strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/prophets-song-gamedoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/prophets-song-gamedoc/</guid>
      <description>Pulling from the following genres
RTS SRPG/Tactical Action RPG MOBA Building/Community Sim AutoBattler/Autochess Survival
overworld rts like ogre battle (see also dragon age map) see also rimworld map
combat mode star ocean dragon age mobas Auto Battlers
Base Building should be able to access all menus from the map. No need to go into deeper detail. Each town has slots for industries and will bring you resources etc. Shops and blacksmiths have levels, you can pay/invest in them as upgrade tiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books to Read</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/books-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/books-to-read/</guid>
      <description>Empire of Imagination - the story of Gary Gygax and D&amp;amp;D Michael Witwer
documentaries to watch Directed by Gary Hustwit Helvetica Objectified Urbanized Workplace Rams - Dieter Rams (Vimeo)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Games and Assets With Fans</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/community-collab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/community-collab/</guid>
      <description>Sony Player Studio
Unreal Tournament (new)
Dota 2 Item Sales
Skyrim - Pay for Mods
Sonic Mania
Real/Original Early Access (Minecraft)
Streaming Designing / Youtube Designing
Level Editors (Warcraft 3, Little Big Planet)
Skyrim Mods</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamelist</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/gamelist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/gamelist/</guid>
      <description>Fire Emblem
Final Fantasy Revenant Wings -DS
GrimGrimoire - PS2 - 2D RTS/SRPG https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GrimGrimoire
13 Sentinels: Aegis Rim - PS4 - Sidescroller/RTS?
Risk - Board Game - Tactical
Dynasty Tactics - PS2 - Tactical/Wargame
Valkyria Chronicles - PS3/PS4 - SRPG/Turn Based Shooter See shining blade and shining ark for psp, they seem similar
Wizardry 8
Darkest Dungeon
Dragon Age: Origins see shining resonance for ps3
Chrono Cross
Star Ocean: The Second Story</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Branding of Game Companies</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/game-branding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/game-branding/</guid>
      <description>brand is how peopele describe your company not what you say.
Final Fantasy Realm Reborn
Warcraft 3 Reforged
Star Wars Battlefront 2</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
