<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Happiness on Mike Brave</title>
    <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/tags/happiness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Happiness on Mike Brave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelbrave.github.io/tags/happiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Awe, Wonder &amp; Pleasant Surprises</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/awe-wonder-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/note/awe-wonder-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Cultivating curiosity and wonder are what allow me to be productive, to get things done and to keep procrastination at bay, I find that they are also core emotions to my functioning well as a person and key my own happiness or contentment.
I believe that the distillation of it is feedback and enjoying that feedback. Look at a baby splashing water, they are surprised by how their actions caused a reaction, they are surprised and often delighted by that direct feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory Of Happiness</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/hapiness-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/hapiness-theory/</guid>
      <description>A Definition
What Makes People Happy?
Mastery - Being good at what you do, competence
Belonging - Social relationships
Autonomy - Freedom to make decisions
Needs satisfied
Happiness is independent of outcomes but we allow our feelings about outcomes to direct it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes That Help You Grow In A Happier Direction</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/happier-direction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/happier-direction/</guid>
      <description>Inviting the World To Play With You
How to play, everything is play
The Homeless Guy In Austin About overcoming fear of Dancing “I Play with you, You Play With Me”
Creating sandboxes to play in, the Wisdom of Teagan
Humility is a Willingness To Learn, an Openness
On Gratitude, The Seed of Happiness
We never achieve things ourselves, we are just a piece of that achievement, your parents raised you, your friends supported you, your society shaped you, you are the core piece, but only a piece, respect and give credit, let them share your accomplishments and achievements because it is theirs too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Strategies And Techniques For A Happier Life</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/happier-life-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/happier-life-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Forgiving Yourself, Forgiving The World I am weak willed at times, be forgiving to yourself Everyone else is just as human as you are, be kind to them. The buddhist idea that life is suffering, so be kind We all kind of suck so be kind to yourself Humanity Is Having Compassion And Suffering With Someone Life Will Provide, You Need Very Little To Live During the camino, people came and went, things sorted themselves out, what you needed was enough, life provided, wisdom was all around, beauty in unlikely places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>knowledge notes</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Relationships and Related Defining Love  What Is Love?  Jon and watching his daughter grow Why I feel loss from distance The need for individuality, love requires friction else it’s an object/slave relationship  Seeing people as people and not just what they can do for you   Often we choose what is familiar instead of what is good for you - some people like to be treated poorly and would be suspicious if you treated them well People who feel like home love shouldn’t have constraints, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit in a box, it’s not negative or fearful, it’s opposite is shame Love is perfect kindness Opening of the heart is the beginning of love There can be many paths and kinds of love, it’s not a hierarchy of strength but different things for different people at different times 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live An Interesting Life</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/living-interesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/living-interesting/</guid>
      <description>Say Yes as Often as You Can
Always Choose The Better Story
What You Want To Do Is Cheaper Than You Think, Find a Way</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pain Isn’t Antagonistic to Happiness, But it’s Easier to Be Happy When Pain is Managed</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/pain-vs-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/pain-vs-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Non-Attachment and Letting Go - Our Expectations are the Painful Part
Goodbyes as an Act of Love - Ash and freeing his pokemon, because he really cared about them
You can’t trust anything to be there tomorrow, people leave or die, currency loses value, governments fail, websites disappear
Every freedom we have could one day disappear, it has happened before, vigilance and care, and a long memory are required to keep it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragedy, Loss and Hope</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/tragedy-loss-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/tragedy-loss-hope/</guid>
      <description>Tragedy and Loss Should Be Treated As the Catalysts of Choice, Show Your Cards or Don’t
It reframes the conflict, now it’s real
The reframing loss/death
These are moments given to us to now choose a path, there is pain, but there is also options of play, we always have some choice to make.
Tragedy is When Poor Choices Are Made, and Consequences Cascade From it
Loss Due to Poor Behavior Feels Like Justice - But it Isn’t</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truly Living</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/truly-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/truly-living/</guid>
      <description>The Point Of The Game Is To Keep Playing, To Play a Beautiful Game
Leap Before You Look - Stop Living a Sterile Life
Avoiding Pain Is Keeping Me From Living
A ship is safe on the docks but that’s not what ships are for.
Inventiveness, Playfulness and Living
There is no reason it can’t be fun
Life Is Resource Management (see boxing)
Really Living vs Being Responsible
A good story doesn’t start with “so I followed the rules and was truly safe”</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>