<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seeing What Is True on Mike Brave</title>
    <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/tags/seeing-what-is-true/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seeing What Is True on Mike Brave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelbrave.github.io/tags/seeing-what-is-true/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Picture Thinking</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/big-picture-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/big-picture-thinking/</guid>
      <description>One of the most productive things I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to do has been to cut things out of my life because they weren&amp;rsquo;t the most important. Focus is as much what you don&amp;rsquo;t do as what you do. So it becomes even more important to recognize and prioritize the things that actually matter, especially if these are along the important and impactful but not urgent spectrum.
So then I have to ask myself, what are the things that actually matter?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Practical Is The Act Of Seeing Through Illusions</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/practical-is-seeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/practical-is-seeing/</guid>
      <description>Instead of buying into the culture/media you can see it as it is
But if you go too far off the path of normal you will be considered insane
Beware of Tinfoil Hat Conspiracy Theories, usually the bigger the theory the less true it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Moralities and The Shifting of Self</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/changing-moralities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/changing-moralities/</guid>
      <description>Morality Is A Kind Of Cowardice, A Conscience Makes Cowards Of Us All
But that isn’t something to look down on, just something to be aware of
“I Don’t Want That Anymore” - Ambitions Change With Life
The tempering of ambitions and how we shift as people
Parents changing direction of what they want to new goals that include or feature their children, it’s not wrong, but it is kinda unexpected</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difficult Truths And How To Accept Them</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/difficult-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/difficult-truths/</guid>
      <description>If it Pisses You Off, There’s a Bit Of Truth in it, Usually&amp;hellip;
It hits hard because you know you should have taken care of it already
A hard truth that needs to be faced
This isn’t always true as sometimes it’s just ridiculous that they even suggest it and it’s angering because of how defamatory it is, but if it was truly ridiculous you would probably laugh instead of getting angry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How People Are</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/how-people-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/how-people-are/</guid>
      <description>Our Flaws Make Us Better - Why It’s Ok for Smart People to Do Dumb Things
I&amp;rsquo;m always shocked when people I admire do dumb things, but never when I do. I don&amp;rsquo;t even look down on them, it&amp;rsquo;s just an “oh, that&amp;rsquo;s odd”. We are all just human. It&amp;rsquo;s better this way
Art Shapes Our Values - Our Surroundings Influence Us
Example - Having Flowers at a school, changes how the school is, how the students treat it and how much learning can take place there</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Is All Around Us, We Just Don’t See It</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/magic-all-around-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/magic-all-around-us/</guid>
      <description>We Often Don’t See Because We Don’t Know How To See Yet
The Hippies Were Right - Undiscovered Things That Matter &amp;amp; Influence
There Is Value In Stating The Obvious
Common Sense is a Lie
The Problem Isn’t The Problem We Think It Is - i.e. Piracy Is About Service, Not Cost
How a Thing Is Communicated Isn’t The Thing Itself
The subject and how it’s communicated, often grouped together, not actually the same thing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing Exists In A Vacuum</title>
      <link>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/nothing-exists-in-a-vacuum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbrave.github.io/drafts/notes/nothing-exists-in-a-vacuum/</guid>
      <description>Everything is Connected, Ecosystems Within Ecosystems
Your body and your mind aren’t separate, similarly your cells and bacteria are part of you too
Dependencies and Chain Reactions
Network Effects
Sometimes a thing by itself won’t do anything, but combined with the right something else will create extraordinary results.
Thinking With Systems
A business is a collection of systems, usually ran by people</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>